# Chidananda Sahu

📞 +918249393800 🗹 sahuchidananda1999@gmail.com in Chidananda 🖸 Chidananda 🜐 Chidananda

#### **FULL - STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

Berhampur, Ganjam Odisha, 760001

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An experienced web developer with two years of experience in the field, specializing in crafting user-friendly web applications, has successfully led various development projects, ensured clear goals, timelines, and effective communication with both stakeholders and team members.

#### **SKILLS**

Technical Skills: Reactjs, Nextjs, Vuejs, Nuxtjs, Javascript, Nodejs, Expressjs, Adonisjs, MongoDB, Html, CSS, Docker

Tools : Firebase, GitHub, git, GitLab, AWS

Soft Skills : Team Work, Problem Solving, Good Communication Skill

#### **EXPERIENCE**

MyFinfi Full Stack Web Developer May 2024 - Present Mumbai, Maharashtra

• Developed a React Super Admin app with Mantine for managing organizations, employees, and plans, with full CRUD functionalities.

• Implemented dark mode and a chatbot-like query and support feature in the Vue.js admin dashboard.

• Created a call component to improve internal communication and optimized the overall dashboard with new features.

• Enhanced user experience by integrating a seamless interface for both mobile and desktop users.

**Edgistify** May 2023 - Mar 2024 Thane, Maharashtra

Full Stack Web Developer

- Collaborated on developing EdgeOS and RMS systems using Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Node.js, and Adonis.js.
- Integrated APIs with courier partners such as DTDC, Xpressbees, and Shiprocket, boosting order fulfillment efficiency by 20%.
- Developed APIs for ecommerce, hyperlocal, and B2B orders, increasing order volume by 30%.

#### Sugar Cosmetics (Vellvette Lifestyle Pvt. Ltd.)

Full Stack Web Developer

May 2022 - May 2023 Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Implemented Juspay frontend using Next.js, improving checkout experience for high-demand products.
- Developed homepage and payment page for Quench Botanics using JavaScript and Next.is, increasing user traffic by 23%.
- Integrated Razorpay for seamless payments on the Quench Botanics website.
- Enhanced user engagement by developing API and animations for the Sugar Fam rewards feature.

### **PROJECTS**

## CS Book ## (7)

• An ebook app where you can discover, download, and read ebooks, as well as learn more about each ebook's description.

**Tech Stack :** Typescript | Next.js | Express.js | Tailwind css

#### Mail-chimp

- A web application that provides mailing, ads, SEO and other e-commercial services
- Build payment page and PayPal payment gateway.

Tech Stack: React | Firebase | firestore | react-redux | paypal | Material UI | Chakra UI | Scss

#### **EDUCATION**

• Masai School: Aug 2021 – Apr 2022 (Full Stack Web development) Bengaluru, Karnataka

• BSc in CS : May 2018 - July 2021 Khallikote, Odisha, IN